Congratulations.
祝贺你！
You've just implemented a full Kalman filter program for
你刚刚实现了一个在二维世界中追踪行人的
tracking a pedestrian in 2D.
完整的卡尔曼滤波器程序
You have used laser measurements to update the 4D state containing the Px,
你使用激光测量值更新了四维状态 包括位置 Px Py
Py position, and Vx, Vy velocity.
以及速度 Vx Vy
But, of course, this model is called sensor fusion.
当然 本章节叫做传感器融合
So, we need to be able to fuse data from another sensor
因此 我们需要融合来自另一个传感器的数据
to improve our object tracking.
改进追踪的效果
So next up, we will integrate radar measurements into our Kalman filter.
接下来 我们会把雷达测量值整合到卡尔曼滤波器中
So how will radar data improve our predictions?
那么 雷达数据会如何改进预测呢？
Although the laser is providing the pedestrian position with high accuracy,
尽管激光提供了很准确的行人位置数据
atually, we don't have yet a way to observe directly its speed.
实际上 我们无法直接观察其速度
That's where radars can help us.
这就是雷达发挥作用的时候了
Using the doppler effect,
根据多普勒效应
the radar can directly measure the radial velocity of a moving object.
雷达能直接测量移动对象的径向速度
The radial velocity is the component of velocity moving towards or
径向速度是指对象靠近或远离传感器的
away from the sensor.
移动速度
However, we also know that the radar has a lower spatial
但是 我们还知道 雷达的空间分辨率
resolution than the laser sensors.
低于激光传感器
So why not combine both of these sensors together?
为什么不把两个传感器结合起来呢？
Let's design our Kalman filter to work with new radar information.
我们来设计一个卡尔曼滤波器 可以利用新的雷达数据
The state transition function will be exactly what you've
这个状态转移函数和你在激光雷达
designed in the LIDAR case.
中设计的完全一样
We use the same state with four parameters, Px, Py, Vx,
我们使用同样的状态 包括四个参数 px、py、vx
Vy with the same linear motion model and process noise.
和 vy 以及同样的线性运动模型和处理误差
However, our new radar sees the world differently.
但是 我们的新雷达观察世界的方式不同
Let's have our vehicle here and the pedestrian here.
我们把车辆放在这里 行人在这里
The x axis always points in the vehicle's direction of movement and
X 轴始终指向车辆的移动方向
the y axis points to the left.
Y 轴指向左边
Instead of a 2D pos, the radar can directly measure the object range,
雷达测量的不是二维数据 它直接测量对象距离
rho, bearing, phi, and range rate, rho dot.
ρ 方向角 φ 以及距离变化率 ρ 点
The range, rho, is the radial distance from the origin to our pedestrian.
距离 ρ 是从原点到行人的径向距离
So we can always define a ray which extends from the origin to our object
因此 我们总能找到一条射线 从原点延伸到
position.
对象位置
The bearing, phi, in this case, is the angle between the ray and x direction.
方向角 φ 是射线和 x 方向的夹角
And the range rate, rho dot,
距离变化率 ρ 点
also known as the radial velocity, is the velocity along this ray.
也叫做径向速度 是沿射线方向的速度
And similar to our motion model,
和我们的运动模型类似
the radar observations are corrupted by a zero-mean random noise, omega.
雷达观察受到均值为0的随机误差 ω 的干扰
Considering that the three measurement vector components are not
考虑到测量向量的三个分量并不
cross-correlated, their radar measurement covariance matrix becomes
互相关联 它们的雷达测量协方差矩阵是
a three-by-three diagonal matrix.
一个 3 乘 3 的对角线矩阵
So, our state is still the same and has four parameters, px, py,
因此 我们的状态仍然相同 有四个参数 Px、Py
vx, vy and the measurement vector has three parameters, rho, phi and rho dot.
Vx、Vy 并且测量向量有三个参数 ρ、φ 和 ρ 点
And the next questing is, what is the measurement function h of x prime,
下一个问题是 把预测的状态 x’ 映射到测量空间的
that maps the predicted state x prime into the measurement space?
测量函数 h(x’) 是多少？
And that's how I define the h function,
我是这么定义 h 函数的
which basically specifies how the predictive position and
它本质上说明了预测位置和
speed can be related to the object range, bearing, and range rate.
速度是如何与对象距离、方向角和距离变化率相关联的
You can find that the derivational disequations below.
你可以在下面找到它们的衍生不等式
Looking at the lowercase h function, you can see that it is a nonlinear function.
看看小写的 h 函数 你会发现这是个非线性函数
So comparing to the linear case when using laser data,
和使用激光数据的线性案例相比
we don't have a measurement matrix, h, here.
我们这里没有测量矩阵
And in the next quiz, I would like to check your intuition.
在下面的练习中 我会检查你的掌握情况